DES FLAHERTY

desflaherty@hotmail.com	0879482820	desflaherty.com
github.com/desflahertyportfolio	in linkedin.com/in/des-flaherty-43b62715	

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Data Analyst who has excellent organisational skills, is highly efficient and has a good eye for detail. Extensive experience of querying warehouse stores and interpreting and analysing data. Highly adaptable with great presentation and design skills. Able to adopt new technologies quickly and with an ability to interact with team members and stakeholders across all levels and departments. Qualified in Data Analytics, Multimedia and recent Software Development graduate.

EXPERIENCE

OCT 2017 - SEPT 2018

INSIGHTS ANALYST, LINKEDIN

- Dealing with ambiguous requests and determining which data is relevant for the brief and how to source and present the information in the most easily understood manner.
- Working across multiple requests simultaneously, managing expectations, and turning data into compelling stories that help LinkedIn's clients become more successful.
- Querying the data warehouse (Teradata, Hadoop) using SQL & Presto and gathering research data and trends from third party sources (Statista and GlobalWebIndex).

MARCH 2014 - JULY 2016

CRM & SALES DATA ANALYST, VODAFONE IRELAND

- Analysis of customer data to identify churn trends and patterns of customer behavior.
- Providing data leads to campaign teams for product offering and customer retention.
- Reporting on business performance KPI's to include new connections, churn, channel performance, NPS scoring and feeding back to stakeholders on a weekly/monthly basis.
- Various projects focused on data management, integration and data quality improvement.

MARCH 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2013

FRAUD ANALYST, DING

- Analysing historic customer transaction data to identify fraudulent trends and patterns.
- Building and implementing new fraud rules into 'Accertify' Fraud Management tool.
- Weekly reporting on Fraud Agent performance KPIs.

DECEMBER 2011 – FEBRUARY 2013

DATA ANALYST, LENOVO

- Reporting on data integrity and escalating to relevant teams ensuring data standards.
- UAT of new CRM software ensuring data accuracy across client portals.
- Automation of manual internal processes to improve team efficiency.

APRIL 2011 – SEPTEMBER 2011

CAMPAIGN ANALYST, EIR

- Generating campaign leads from various sources according to marketing campaign briefs.
- Liaising with requestors on re-design of campaign briefs and data related queries.

APRIL 2010 - APRIL 2011

CRM SPECIALIST. MSD IRELAND

- Conducting CRM training workshops for new Sales Reps and Managers and providing helpdesk support.
- Generating monthly financial sales data reports and distributing to the senior leadership team and key stakeholders.

♣ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2009 – APRIL 2010, COMMERCIAL ADMINISTRATOR, STAPLES ADVANTAGE

OCTOBER 2008 – APRIL 2009, SAP DATA ANALYST, DEPARTMENT OF ENVIRONMENT, SYDNEY

AUGUST 2007 – APRIL 2008, CLINICAL PROGRAMMER, QUINTILES IRELAND

SEPTEMBER 2006 – AUGUST 2007, DATABASE ADMINISTRATOR, ICON CLINICAL

MAY 2006 – SEPTEMBER 2006, SAP HELPDESK, ALLERGAN PHARMACEUTICALS

JULY 2004 – APRIL 2006, SAP MASTER DATA ADMINISTRATOR, ABBOTT

EDUCATION

OCT 2018 – MAY 2019, DIPLOMA IN FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT (FIRST CLASS HONOURS), CODE INSTITUTE

SEPT 2012- MAY 2014, POSTGRADUATE DIPLOMA DATA ANALYTICS (2.1), DUBLIN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

SEPT 2002- MAY 2004, BSC HONS MULTIMEDIA COMPUTING (2.1), SWANSEA UNIVERSITY AUGUST 2001- JUNE 2002, DIPLOMA WEB & MULTIMEDIA AUTHORING (2.1), DUN LAOGHAIRE FURTHER EDUCATION INSTITUTE

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- ✓ SQL
- ✓ EXCEL
- ✓ ACCESS
- ✓ POWERPOINT
- ✓ TABLEAU
- ✓ SALESFORCE CRM
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS & BOOTSTRAP
- ✓ PYTHON/DJANGO/FLASK
- ✓ BALSAMIQ

KNOWLEDGE & PERSONAL

- ✓ SQL QUERYING (TERADATA, SQL SERVER, ORACLE, HADOOP, MONGODB)
- ✓ DATA VALIDATION & MANIPULATION
- ✓ VISUALIZATION
- ✓ INTERFACE & WEB DESIGN
- ✓ DATA ANALYSIS
- ✓ PRESENTATIONS
- ✓ PROBLEM SOLVING
- ✓ CREATIVITY
- ✓ TEAM-WORK